[
    {
        "question": " ........... is the first woman to head a public sector bank.",
        "optionA": "Arundhati Bhattacharya",
        "optionB": "Shikha Sharma ",
        "optionC": "Chanda Kochar",
        "optionD": "Usha Ananthasubramanyan",
        "answer": "Arundhati Bhattacharya"
    },

    {
        "question": "World Tourism Day is celebrated on",
        "optionA": "September 12",
        "optionB": "September 25",
        "optionC": "September 27",
        "optionD": "September 29",
        "answer": "September 27"
    },

    {
        "question": "Where is Bose Institute?",
        "optionA": "Dispur",
        "optionB": "Kolkata",
        "optionC": "Mumbai",
        "optionD": "New Delhi",
        "answer": "Kolkata"
    },

    {
        "question": "When is the International Yoga Day celebrated?",
        "optionA": "June 21",
        "optionB": "March 21",
        "optionC": "December 21",
        "optionD": "None of these",
        "answer": "June 21"
    },

    {
        "question": "The two-day festival 'North East Calling', is organized by which ministry?",
        "optionA": "Ministry of Development of North Eastern Region (DoNER)",
        "optionB": "Ministry of External Affairs",
        "optionC": "Ministry of Home Affairs",
        "optionD": "Ministry of Defence",
        "answer": "Ministry of Development of North Eastern Region (DoNER)"
    },

    {
        "question": "The motif of 'Hampi with Chariot' is printed on the reverse of which currency note?",
        "optionA": "One Rupee Note",
        "optionB": "Rs. 500 note",
        "optionC": "Rs. 10000 note",
        "optionD": "Rs. 50 note",
        "answer": "Rs. 50 note"
    },

    {
        "question": "'Line of Blood' is a book written by whom?",
        "optionA": "Bairaj Khanna",
        "optionB": "Ursula Vernon ",
        "optionC": "Amal EI-Mohtar",
        "optionD": "Diksha Basu",
        "answer": "Bairaj Khanna"
    },

    {
        "question": "What does the roman numeral C represent?",
        "optionA": "100",
        "optionB": "10",
        "optionC": "10,000",
        "optionD": "1,000,000",
        "answer": "100"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which state launch a project that aims to provide free internet access to the poor in the State?",
        "optionA": "Kerela",
        "optionB": "Bihar",
        "optionC": "Mizoram",
        "optionD": "Haryana",
        "answer": "Kerela"
    },

    {
        "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
        "optionA": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "optionB": "Sir Isaac Newton",
        "optionC": "Leonardo Da Vinci",
        "optionD": "Albert Einstein",
        "answer": "Leonardo Da Vinci"
    },

    {
        "question": "What is the Height of Iffil Tower in Paris",
        "optionA": "324 meter",
        "optionB": "286 meter",
        "optionC": "386 meter",
        "optionD": "392 meter",
        "answer": "324 meter"
    },

    {
        "question": "Name the first cricketer to score 1000 runs in an innings in any competitive match",
        "optionA": "Prithvi Shaw",
        "optionB": "Pranav Dhanawade",
        "optionC": "Virat Kohl",
        "optionD": "Shikhar Dhawan",
        "answer": "Pranav Dhanawade"
    },

    {
        "question": " According to international standard, what is the distance of marathon race?",
        "optionA": "26 miles 385 yards",
        "optionB": "20 miles 750 yards",
        "optionC": "36 miles 450 yards",
        "optionD": "25 miles 575 yards",
        "answer": "26 miles 385 yards"
    },

    {
        "question": "Beighton Cup is associated with which of the following?",
        "optionA": "Cricket",
        "optionB": "Hockey",
        "optionC": "Football",
        "optionD": "Volleyball",
        "answer": "Hockey"
    },

    {
        "question": "The super computer ‘PARAM’ was developed by",
        "optionA": "TATA",
        "optionB": "IIT - Kharagpur",
        "optionC": "IIT Madras",
        "optionD": "C-DAC",
        "answer": "C-DAC"
    }
]